Ashley Clarke

Portfolio | Seattle, Wa | 360.990.6669 | crashley92@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with years of experience conducting online investigations and community management. A desire to learn cyber security lead to studying new technologies and web development through self-taught coding skills. Hands on experience with writing SQL queries and proficiency in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Acquired MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js) stack education via University of Washington's coding bootcamp.

HTML5 · CSS3 · Bootstrap · JavaScript (ESS/ES6) · jQuery · React · Node.js · MongoDB · SQL/MySQL Workbench · Express · Heroku · Jira · Git · MERN Stack

Education & Certifications

Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR

B.S of Psychology - JUNE 2016

Attended Oregon State University while under scholarship for ARMY ROTC, and as an enlisted member of the Oregon State ARMY National Guard.

- Earned several awards for Physical Fitness and recognized by Battalion Command Sergeant Major for superior fitness.
- Assisted with founding the Oregon State Boxing Club and became a collegiate member.

University of Washington Coding Bootcamp, Seattle, WA CERTIFICATE- JANUARY 2020

Attended University of Washington Professional Education Program for full stack web development, specializing in the MERN stack.

- Completed 16 projects and 3 group projects.
- Lead, created the idea for, and managed 3/3 group projects.
- Presented and demoed group project apps to class and instructor team.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Xbox Community Manager

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

Microsoft (Consultant via JeffreyM Consulting), Bellevue, WA

Execute reactive social media engagement and social listening strategies to create an inclusive and active community with Xbox console users across multiple platforms including Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, and YouTube.

• Made **9.2k** posts betweem Twitter, YouTube, Instagram, and Facebook resulting in **139,153** Post Likes and Reactions, **4,885** Post Comments, **5,001** Post Shares, and **5,995** Source Clicks.

Social AI Community Manager

SEPTEMBER 2018 - JANUARY 2019

Microsoft (Consultant via JeffreyM Consulting), Bellevue, WA

Execute team and social strategy for artificial intelligence through use of social listening, paid advertising, and collaboration with influencers across multiple platforms. Conducted proactive investigations into trolling communities such as 4chan and escalated possible negative Public Relations incidents to Project Management.

• Unable to disclose explicit details about project due to Non Disclosure Agreements (NDA)

Xbox Live Online Safety Investigator

DECEMBER 2015 - JANUARY 2018

Microsoft (Consultant via Apex Systems), Bellevue, WA

Traiged Xbox Live Public and Cyber safety threats through deep dive investigations and data analysis.

- Responded to user and internal/external team reports of abusive or threatening online behaviors.
- Conducted fraud related incident management for external partners.
- Analyzed data sets using SQL and COSMOS to proactively find accounts conducting malicious behaviors.
- Participated in a mentorship program to assist with team mental wellness and career development.
- Contacted local law enforcement agencies to respond to public and self-harm threats.
- Developed more reformative behaviors with Xbox customers who conducted service agreements.

Projects

Fraud Prevention Query: Wrote a query after noticing irregular data sets in accounts that were using stolen credit cards.

Dossing and Doxing Query: Wrote a query to proactively found accounts making online safety threats.